RAGHAV AGGARWAL

+91-7042266811 • raghavaggarwal200004@gmail.com • GitHub • LinkedIn • Leetcode • Portfolio

PROFILE SUMMARY

Technology-driven Software Engineer with 2.6 years of experience in translating business requirements and functional specifications into code modules and innovative solutions. Deep understanding of Software Development Life Cycle and Innovative Technologies such as full stack Mobile, Web Applications, and Chatbot development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Technology Parks Of India

Aug 2024 - Present

MERN Stack Developer

- 1. Led the development of Phase 2 for the Sayuj social media platform, integrating key features such as real-time notifications, customizable user profiles, and activity feeds to boost user engagement.
- Strengthened platform security by implementing JWT-based authentication, role-based access control (RBAC), and robust data validation using Mongoose, ensuring data integrity and secure user access.

Plutos One(Fintech)

Sept 2023 – July 2024

Software Developer Engineer

- 1. Created WhatsApp and Web Chatbot using React and Python (Rasa and Llama Index) from scratch, supporting 15+ languages using Google API, Bhasini, and actively used by 100,000+ users.
- 2. Creation of TSP(Technology service providers) & SaaS(Software as a service) for banks and worked with NPCI (National Payment Corporation of India) and enabled their users to pay their bills hassle-free.
- 3. Implementing BBPS GPT (Generative Pre-trained Transformer) for bill Payments for VISA, BOB, IDBI, etc.

Blocktickets.io Full Stack Developer

June 2022 - Aug 2023

- 1. Launched a secure and scalable ticketing system backend, ensuring high performance under heavy load.
- 2. Designed the system architecture & optimized RESTful APIs to streamline data flow & improve user transaction speed.

SKILLS

- Languages: C, C++, JavaScript, Python
- Frameworks and Tools: Node.js, Express.js, React.js Django, Rasa, Ollama
- DSA, Redux, AWS, GitHub(Version Control), Git, MySQL, Socket.io, Postman, BullMq, Postgresql, Docker-compose, Websockets, Responsive Web Design, Jest, Agile Methodologies, Database Querving
- Non-Technical Skills: Teamwork, Collaboration, Communication, Adaptability and Multi-tasking, Innovative

PROJECTS

Plutos ONE Chatbot (Skills: Rasa, Python, Django React.JS)

Dec 2023 -July 2024

- 1. Developed an efficient and stable web chatbot using Rasa and Django.
- 2. Created Whatsapp chatbot using GupShup API for communication between server and WhatsApp
- 3. Implemented **Openhermes LLM** for semantic search
- Responsible for syncing operations into **Redis** using valid **Data structures** for faster API response.

Block tickets E-commerce (Skills: MERN, JavaScript, S3, EC2)

Mar 2023 – Aug 2023

- 1. Implemented robust APIs for a ticket-selling platform, along with an admin panel for event upgrades and order management.
- Integrated third-party services, including Cloud APIs, Nodemailer for ticket information and verification emails, and Cashfree for secure payment processing.
- 3. **Deployed the application on AWS EC2**, utilizing S3 for efficient image storage and management.

Live chat Application (Skills: MERN, JWT, Socket.io, Cloudinary, Chakra UI, CSS)

Jan 2022 - May 2022

- 1. **Built a real-time live chat app** with MERN, using Socket.io for multi-user rooms.
- 2. Integrated Chakra UI for a responsive UI and Cloudinary for seamless image uploads. (GitHub) (Deployment)

Rate Limiter Middleware (Skills: Node.js, Cookies)

July 2021 – July 2021

1. Engineered a reusable rate limiter middleware to restrict API access per IP, enhancing security. (GitHub)

EDUCATION

Galgotias College of Engineering and Technology affiliated to AKTU

Master's Degree in Computer Application Development (MCA)

Jagannath Institute of Management Studies affiliated to IPU

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (BCA)

Nov 2021 - June 2023 Percentage: 74%

July 2018 - May 2021

Percentage: 80.5%